# BHUSHAN PATIL () Featured

Ab initio developer with 4.4 year experience. Seeking roles in Application Development, Application Maintenance, Application Support, Requirement Analysis, Debugging, Bug Fixing, Coding, Ab Initio, Shell Scripting, Source Tree, Putty, GDE. SAS



Current Designation: Abinitio Developer Total Experience: 4 Year(s) 4 Month(s)

Current Company: Barclays Technology Notice Period: 15 Days or less

Current Location: Pune Highest Degree: B.Tech/B.E. [Computers]

Pref. Location: Mumbai, Pune

Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance

Role: Software Developer

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Single/unmarried

Key Skills: Debugging, Bug Fixing, Coding, Ab Initio, SourceTree, Putty, SAS, Unix, SQL, ETL Tool, Tivoli Workload

Scheduler, Agile, Scrum, Waterfall, Application Support, Abinitio Developer

Verified: Phone Number | Email - id

Last Active: 22-Jan-21 Last Modified: 22-Jan-21

## **Summary**

Around 4.1 Years of Experience in Ab Initio Technology.

Proven track record of successful implementation of all project life cycle stages from requirements gathering through implementation and enhancements.

Created and maintained Ab Initio Graphs using various components like Join, Rollup, Reformat, Scan, Filter by Expression, Partition Components.

Good working experience with all components in GDE. Creating, Executing, Testing and maintaining the graphs in Ab Initio.

Participate in unit testing and integration testing.

Develop technical specification documents.

Good experience with Version control systems and Issue tracking systems.

Coordinate third level Production support and release implementations activities.

Comfortable with Linux environment and has ability to create automation shell scripts as needed.

Banking or financial services experience.

Good written and communication skills with ability to articulate ideas and issues in a team environment.

# **Work Experience**

Barclays Technology as Abinitio Developer

Nov 2015 to Mar 2020

Abinitio developer

Barclays Technology as Abinitio Developer

Nov 2015 to Mar 2020

Developing various graphs as per the business requirements.

Understanding the functional requirement document.

Build the graphs for analyzing the data.

Writing the UNIX shell scripting for automating the things.

Developing graphs using various components such as Reformat, validate, Join, Rollup, Sort etc.

Involved in daily meeting for discussing about defect fixes

#### Barclays Technology Centre of India as Software Engineer

Nov 2015 to Mar 2020

Project 1: Group Capital Reporting

Role: GCR ABI Developer

Project Description: The GCR project is a part of Basel II Group Reporting Programme. Its main purpose is to ensure that Barclays is able to produce Risk Weighted Asset(RWA) calculations across the group and submit Basel II compliant reports with the timescale laid down by the regulators.

Within GCR as a whole, the purpose of the Ab -initio ETL layer is to validate and process IFF data files from Clusters, SAP ZE ledger files and reference data, and load them into SAS Transitory Detail Data store.

Responsibilities:

Developing various graphs as per the business requirements.

Understanding the functional requirement document.

Build the graphs for analyzing the data.

Writing the UNIX shell scripting for automating the things.

Developing graphs using various components such as Reformat, validate, Join, Rollup, Sort etc.

Involved in daily meeting for discussing about defect fixes

Project 2: Auto Decisioning Role: Software Engineer

Project Description: Auto Decision is part of Barclaycard Merchant services. While onboarding any merchant AD plays a key role by applying and validating rule over merchant fulfillment request. AD identify/validate the merchant portfolio with help of data captured by multiple source and direct business intervention.

Responsibilities:

Extracted data from oracle and flat files.

Used Sort component to sort the table, and used dedup sort to remove duplicate values.

Used Rollup component to populate monthly, quarterly and annual summary tables.

Designed Test scenario for unit testing and system testing.

Maintained process and quality documentation.

Have good knowledge of UNIX Scripting.

#### Barclays Technology as Abinitio Developer

Nov 2015 to Mar 2020

Developing various graphs as per the business requirements.

Understanding the functional requirement document.

Build the graphs for analyzing the data.

Writing the UNIX shell scripting for automating the things.

Developing graphs using various components such as Reformat, validate, Join, Rollup, Sort etc.

Involved in daily meeting for discussing about defect fixes

#### Barclays Technology as Abinitio Developer

Nov 2015 to Till Date

Developing various graphs as per the business requirements.

Understanding the functional requirement document.

Build the graphs for analyzing the data.

Writing the UNIX shell scripting for automating the things.

Developing graphs using various components such as Reformat, validate, Join, Rollup, Sort etc.

Involved in daily meeting for discussing about defect fixes

#### Barclays Technology as Abinitio Developer

Nov 2015 to Mar 2020

### **Education**

UG: B.Tech/B.E. (Computers) from Pune University in 2015

#### IT Skills

Skill Name	Version	Last Used	Experience
Ab Initio			
Shell Scripting			

1/22/2021 https://freesearch.naukri.com/preview/printResume?uname=4662a25f114ce24edb4c6eda407fb10e5f5c5d524d465a170643140d550...

Source Tree		
Putty, SAS		
Tivol		
Oracle, MS SQL		
Ab Initio	2020	4 Year(s) 0 Month(s)

# Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
English				
Hindi				
Marathi				

### **Affirmative Action**

Category: General

Physically Challenged: No

### **Work Authorization**

Job Type: Permanent

Employment Status: Full time